<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>aafu theme on </title>
    <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in aafu theme on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 27 (2025/3/4)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/25_3_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/25_3_4/</guid>
      <description>OTA-Summary N. K. Jha, H. Guo and V. K. N. Lau, &amp;ldquo;Analog Product Coding for Over-the-Air Aggregation Over Burst-Sparse Interference Multiple-Access Channels,&amp;rdquo; in IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing, vol. 72, pp. 157-172, 2024, doi: 10.1109/TSP.2023.3338046.&#xA;Introduction Problem: Over-the-Air aggregation (OTA) is a promising technology for Internet-of-Things (IoT) applications, but it can be vulnerable to burst interference from co-channel non-cooperative IoT communications.&#xA;Solutions: A robust OTA framework for IoT-OTA applications that mitigates burst sparse interference using analog product code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 26 (2025/2/25)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/25_2_25/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/25_2_25/</guid>
      <description>Blind Federated Learning via Over-the-Air q-QAM Saeed Razavikia, José Mairton Barros da Silva, and Carlo Fischione. 2024. Blind Federated Learning via Over-the-Air q-QAM. Trans. Wireless. Comm. 23, 12_Part_2 (Dec. 2024), 19570–19586. https://doi.org/10.1109/TWC.2024.3485117.&#xA;Basic Introduction Federated edge learning over a fading multiple access channel.&#xA;To alleviate the communication burden between the edge devices and the access point, we introduce a pioneering digital over-the-air computation strategy employing q-ary quadrature amplitude modulation, culminating in a low latency communication scheme.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 25 (2025/2/18)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/25_2_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/25_2_18/</guid>
      <description>Channel Model between Satellites and Ground Station O. Y. Kolawole, S. Vuppala, M. Sellathurai and T. Ratnarajah, &amp;ldquo;On the Performance of Cognitive Satellite-Terrestrial Networks,&amp;rdquo; in IEEE Transactions on Cognitive Communications and Networking, vol. 3, no. 4, pp. 668-683, Dec. 2017, doi: 10.1109/TCCN.2017.2763619.&#xA;Abstract We investigate the performance of a multi-beam cognitive satellite terrestrial network in which a secondary network (mobile terrestrial system) shares resources with a primary satellite network given that the interference temperature constraint is satisfied.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 23 (2025/2/12)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/25_2_12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/25_2_12/</guid>
      <description>END-TO-END OPTIMIZED IMAGE COMPRESSION Johannes Balle ́, Valero Laparra, and Eero P. Simoncelli. End-to-end optimized image compression. In ICLR, 2017.&#xA;http://arxiv.org/abs/1611.01704&#xA;Code: https://github.com/tensorflow/compression?utm_source=catalyzex.com (Tensorflow)&#xA;https://github.com/jorge-pessoa/pytorch-gdn?utm_source=catalyzex.com (pytorch)&#xA;Abstract We describe an image compression method, consisting of a nonlinear analysis transformation, a uniform quantizer, and a nonlinear synthesis transformation. The transforms are constructed in three successive stages of convolutional linear filters and nonlinear activation functions. Unlike most convolutional neural networks, the joint nonlinearity is chosen to implement a form of local gain control, inspired by those used to model biological neurons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 22 (2025/1/22)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/25_1_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/25_1_23/</guid>
      <description>Learning End-to-End Lossy Image Compression: A Benchmark Y. Hu, W. Yang, Z. Ma and J. Liu, &amp;ldquo;Learning End-to-End Lossy Image Compression: A Benchmark,&amp;rdquo; in IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence, vol. 44, no. 8, pp. 4194-4211, 1 Aug. 2022, doi: 10.1109/TPAMI.2021.3065339.&#xA;Code: GitHub - huzi96/Coarse2Fine-PyTorch&#xA;Abstract Image compression is one of the most fundamental techniques and commonly used applications in the image and video processing field. Earlier methods built a well-designed pipeline, and efforts were made to improve all modules of the pipeline by handcrafted tuning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 21 (2025/1/15)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/25_1_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/25_1_15/</guid>
      <description>Communication-Efficient Learning of Deep Networks from Decentralized Data (FedAvg) McMahan, H. B., Moore, E., Ramage, D., Hampson, S., and Agüera y Arcas, B., “Communication-Efficient Learning of Deep Networks from Decentralized Data”, arXiv e-prints, Art. no. arXiv:1602.05629, 2016. doi:10.48550/arXiv.1602.05629.&#xA;Background Federated Learning: Ideal problems for federated learning have the following properties:&#xA;Training on real-world data from mobile devices provides a distinct advantage over training on proxy data that is generally available in the data center.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 20 (2025/1/8)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/25_1_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/25_1_8/</guid>
      <description>A General Theory for Federated Optimization with Asynchronous and Heterogeneous Clients Updates — Investigation on $q_i(n)$ and $\omega_i(n)$ and part of the proof Fraboni Y, Vidal R, Kameni L, et al. A general theory for federated optimization with asynchronous and heterogeneous clients updates[J]. Journal of Machine Learning Research, 2023, 24(110): 1-43.&#xA;Code: Accenture/Labs-Federated-Learning at asynchronous_FL&#xA;Background For FedAvg, the aggregation scheme can be considered as,&#xA;$$ \theta^{n+1} := \theta^n +\sum_{i=1}^M p_i \Delta_i(n) $$</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 19 (2025/1/1)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/25_1_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/25_1_1/</guid>
      <description>A General Theory for Federated Optimization with Asynchronous and Heterogeneous Clients Updates Fraboni Y, Vidal R, Kameni L, et al. A general theory for federated optimization with asynchronous and heterogeneous clients updates[J]. Journal of Machine Learning Research, 2023, 24(110): 1-43.&#xA;Code: Accenture/Labs-Federated-Learning at asynchronous_FL&#xA;Ⅰ. Background 1. Asynchronicity in Clients Updates For Server: An optimization round starts at time $t^n$ with global model $\theta^n$. Finishing at time $t^{n+1}$ with the new global model $\theta^{n+1}$, which takes $\Delta t^n = t^{n+1}- t^n$ to complete.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 18.1 (2024/12/25)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_12_25_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_12_25_1/</guid>
      <description>Cyclic Client Federated Learning [1] [1] Cho Y J, Sharma P, Joshi G, et al. On the convergence of federated averaging with cyclic client participation[C]//International Conference on Machine Learning. PMLR, 2023: 5677-5721.&#xA;Abstract Federated Averaging (FedAvg) and its variants are the most popular optimization algorithms in federated learning (FL). Previous convergence analyses of FedAvg either assume full client participation or partial client participation where the clients can be uniformly sampled.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 18.2 (2024/12/25)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_12_25_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_12_25_2/</guid>
      <description>AFL (Broadcast to All Clients) [1] Koloskova A, Stich S U, Jaggi M. Sharper convergence guarantees for asynchronous SGD for distributed and federated learning[J]. Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems, 2022, 35: 17202-17215.&#xA;Abstract We study the asynchronous stochastic gradient descent algorithm for distributed training over $n$ workers which have varying computation and communication frequency over time. In this algorithm, workers compute stochastic gradients in parallel at their own pace and return those to the server without any synchronization.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 17 (2024/12/18)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_12_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_12_18/</guid>
      <description>Summary &amp;mdash; {12.18} FedFusion: Manifold-Driven Federated Learning for Multi-Satellite and Multi-Modality Fusion D. Li, W. Xie, Y. Li and L. Fang, &amp;ldquo;FedFusion: Manifold-Driven Federated Learning for Multi-Satellite and Multi-Modality Fusion,&amp;rdquo; in IEEE Transactions on Geoscience and Remote Sensing, vol. 62, pp. 1-13, 2024, Art no. 5500813, doi: 10.1109/TGRS.2023.3339522.&#xA;Problems and Motivations Multi-Satellite, multi-modality in-orbit fusion is a challenging task as it explores the fusion representation of complex high-dimensional data under limited computational resources.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 15 (2024/11/27)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_11_27/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_11_27/</guid>
      <description>“3GPP” Release 18 NTN Summary Policy and Charging Control (PCC) and Quality of Service (QoS) control considering dynamic satellite backhaul While using satellites as the backhaul, a gNB may be subject to variable backhaul delay or bandwidth if the backhaul connection involves varying inter-satellite links or if it has different types of satellite backhaul. The change of satellite backhaul delay has impact to PCC/QoS control, hence following enhancements are introduced:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 14 (2024/11/20)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_11_20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_11_20/</guid>
      <description>ALANINE: A Novel Decentralized Personalized Federated Learning For Heterogeneous LEO Satellite Constellation (Arxiv 2024.11) Abstract Low Earth Orbit (LEO) satellite constellations have seen significant growth and functional enhancement in recent years, which integrates various capabilities like communication, navigation, and remote sensing. However, the heterogeneity of data collected by different satellites and the problems of efficient inter-satellite collaborative computation pose significant obstacles to realizing the potential of these constellations. Existing approaches struggle with data heterogeneity, varing image resolutions, and the need for efficient on-orbit model training.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 13.1 (2024/11/13)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_11_13_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_11_13_1/</guid>
      <description>Inter-Satellites Link Communication Channel Channel Modeling and Analysis of Inter-Small-Satellite Links in Terahertz Band Space Networks S. Nie and I. F. Akyildiz, &amp;ldquo;Channel Modeling and Analysis of Inter-Small-Satellite Links in Terahertz Band Space Networks,&amp;rdquo; in IEEE Transactions on Communications, vol. 69, no. 12, pp. 8585-8599, Dec. 2021, doi: 10.1109/TCOMM.2021.3113942.&#xA;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/9541155&#xA;This paper mostly focus on when the size of the satellite is small enough.&#xA;Our numerical results demonstrate that:&#xA;the ionospheric plasma does not affect the THz band signal propagation in near-Earth orbits; (ionospheric plasma will cause multipath.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 13.2 (2024/11/13)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_11_13_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_11_13_2/</guid>
      <description>Data Compression Works on Satellites https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10283385&#xA;This paper provide datasets on Hyperspectral images, which is an important part in satellite datasets.&#xA;Towards Efficient Satellite Computing Through Adaptive Compression&#xA;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?tp=&amp;amp;arnumber=10697471.&#xA;This is a paper for clarify data on the satellite and then compress it to improve the overall efficiency.&#xA;C. Yang et al., &amp;ldquo;Towards Efficient Satellite Computing Through Adaptive Compression,&amp;rdquo; in IEEE Transactions on Services Computing, doi: 10.1109/TSC.2024.3470341.&#xA;Two Main Problems:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 12 (2024/11/06)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_11_06/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_11_06/</guid>
      <description>Communication channel model between LEO satellite and Ground User For the LEOS communications, the altitude, speed and position information of the LEOS are known to all BSs in a time slot. For the sake of simplicity, a quasi-static fading channel model is considered in a time slot. Thus, the signal received by the LEOS over the $Ka$-band is given by,&#xA;$$ y = \sqrt{p}h^{Ka}s+N_0, $$&#xA;$y$ is the received signal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 11 (2024/10/30)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_10_30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_10_30/</guid>
      <description>FOOL: Addressing the Downlink Bottleneck in Satellite Computing with Neural Feature Compression https://arxiv.org/abs/2403.16677.&#xA;Quick Summary: LEO will generate lots of data in a short time, but the maximum transmission capability is limited. In this case, we hope we can only transmit part of the most important data to the ground station and try to recover them. This paper provide an interesting view that satellite usually compress data in a long time but have to transmit the data in a short time because it can only transm</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 10 (2024/10/23)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_10_23/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_10_23/</guid>
      <description>https://api.starlink.com/public-files/DIRECT_TO_CELL_FIRST_TEXT_UPDATE.pdf&#xA;Here is a report from SpaceX. As they said, current communication between phone and satellite still have problems.&#xA;Mobility Management in Satellite SKYCASTLE: Taming LEO Mobility to Facilitate Seamless and Low-latency Satellite Internet Services https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10621390/?arnumber=10621390.&#xA;The fundamental challenge stems from a unique characteristic of ISTNs: not only users are mobile, but also core network infrastructures (i.e., LEO satellites) are frequently changing their locations in the network.&#xA;Research scope Firstly, efficiently integrate satellite constellations into existing terrestrial Internet, emerging ISTNs like Starlink adopts IP-based networking architecture with heterogeneous wireless access technologies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 9 (2024/10/16)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_10_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_10_16/</guid>
      <description>Graph Tensor Completion Preliminary: Basic Notations: Assume $\mathcal A$ is a third order tensor, $A$ is a matrix and $a$ is a vector.&#xA;$G(V, E, A)$ be a graph with $N$ nodes, where $V$ is the set of nodes, $E$ is the set of edges and $A$ is the adjacency matrix of size $N\times N$.&#xA;Laplacian matrix $L=D-A$ can describe the connection information of nodes.&#xA;$D = diag(d_1, d_2, …, d_n)$ is the degree matrix, and $d_i=\sum_{j} A_{ij}$.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 8 (2024/10/09)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_10_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_10_9/</guid>
      <description>Important materials: Below is an important survey paper on STN computing. (2023.10.15)&#xA;http://www.tiansuan.org.cn/Chinese/source/Satellite_Computing_Vision_and_Challenges.pdf&#xA;This paper provide a comprehensive view on computing in space. Based on their experiments in real satellite, they provide different kinds of problems which need further works.&#xA;Below are two important demo for satellite network.&#xA;https://www.uni.lu/research-en/research-areas/space-systems/&#xA;This is a demo from University of Luxembourg. Even though they do not use real satellite, but they try to use different methods to emulate the communication environment in the space, which a good alternative way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 7.1 (2024/9/25)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_9_25_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_9_25_1/</guid>
      <description>Important Papers (STN Offloading) Two-Timescale Learning-Based Task Offloading for Remote IoT in Integrated Satellite–Terrestrial Networks&#xA;STN for sensitive task offloading in remote IoT devices.&#xA;Optimization problems on offloading link selection and bandwidth allocation. Also divide the problems into two subproblems to make computing time scalable.&#xA;Solutions: H-PPO, Discrete + continuous hybrid model&#xA;Multi-BS, Multi-satellites and Multi-users.&#xA;This paper considers that both the base station and LEO node are non-computing nodes, which need to be offloaded to the core network for calculation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 7.2 (2024/9/25)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_9_25_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_9_25_2/</guid>
      <description>Important papers (Networking for FL) AOP: Towards Adaptive Offloading Point Approach in a Federated Learning Framework for Edge AI Applications&#xA;Offloading the AI training to edge nodes.&#xA;Using RL method to decide which DNN should be offloaded to the edge and using clustering algorithm to assist this process.&#xA;The Architecture of Computing Power Network Towards Federated Learning: Paradigms and Perspectives&#xA;Introducing the concept of computing power network.&#xA;Because of the computing resources in different devices, it will introduce heterogeneity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 7.3 (2024/9/25)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_9_25_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_9_25_3/</guid>
      <description>Smart Farm Telemedicine: Remote medical consultations, diagnostics, and even surgeries rely on high-speed communication networks and advanced computing for real-time data processing, image analysis, and secure patient data management. Smart Grids: These systems use long-distance communication to monitor and manage electricity distribution. They require substantial computing power for real-time data analysis, predictive maintenance, and optimizing energy usage across vast networks. Autonomous Vehicles: Self-driving cars and drones depend on long-distance communication for navigation, traffic updates, and coordination with other vehicles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 6 (2024/9/18)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_9_18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_9_18/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Four kinds of typical satellites:&#xA;GEO (Geostationary Earth Orbit): About 36,000 kilometers. MEO (Middle Earth Orbit): The orbital altitude is between 2000 and 36,000 km. (GPS) LEO (Low Earth Orbit): The orbital altitude is about 600-2000 km. VLEO (Very Low Earth Orbit): Nearly 350 km. (Low transmission delay, low propagation loss, high regional capacity, and low manufacturing and launch costs) Huawei Pay attention to Satellites in this orbit. https://www.huawei.com/cn/huaweitech/future-technologies/very-low-earth-orbit-satellite-networks-6g. The red part will be the latency of NTN.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 5 (2024/9/11)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_9_11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_9_11/</guid>
      <description>In this record, I decide to show some papers which let me have new ideas, mostly focus on what they do, what are their problems and how we can solve them.&#xA;Firstly, I would like to give a relatively detailed decribetion on deep unrolling.&#xA;Deep unrolling involves transforming an iterative optimization algorithm into a neural network. Each iteration of the algorithm is represented as a layer in the network. This approach leverages the strengths of both traditional model-based methods and data-driven deep learning techniques.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 4 (2024/8/21)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_8_21/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_8_21/</guid>
      <description>This week, I&amp;rsquo;m going to present two intriguing solutions, both related to the use of GNNs, for potentially implementing a fair cloud trading system as previously discussed.&#xA;Dynamic Graph Neural Network Graph Neural Networks (GNNs) are an efficient method for processing data structured as graphs and have seen widespread adoption. However, the majority of existing GNNs are designed to work with static graphs, which do not change once node and edge features have been defined.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 3 (2024/8/14)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_8_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_8_14/</guid>
      <description>Details about Fair Financial Exchanges In this week&amp;rsquo;s report, I aim to detail the evaluation process of my idea.&#xA;Distribution Delay The first aspect I want to assess is the propagation delay. The evaluation process is outlined as follows:&#xA;Design a network topology that supports multiple carriers to ensure consistency in both time period and network environment. Incrementally add market participants into the market and monitor the total delay observed. This section aims to test the distribution latency, essentially determining whether the method can guarantee that the information delivered to the user end is both timely and relevant.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 2 (2024/8/7)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_8_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_8_7/</guid>
      <description>Fair Financial Transactions on Cloud Driven by Graph Neural Networks&#xA;Background Currently, migrating financial transactions to public cloud platforms is becoming increasingly popular in the industry. This is because cloud services offer flexibility, stability, and cost savings compared to traditional local configurations.&#xA;However, moving to the public cloud also presents several challenges. Firstly, each market participant (MP) needs to receive financial transaction information simultaneously to ensure they all have the same reaction time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning Record --- 1 (2024/7/31)</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_7_31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/24_7_31/</guid>
      <description>My Last Work Review Firstly, I would like to introduce my last work in detail. We design a new framework based on Neural Representation for Videos (NeRV), which can efficiently transform a video compression task into a neural network compression task by using the idea of Implicit Neural Representation (INR).&#xA;Before delving into how NeRV addresses specific challenges and its respective advantages and disadvantages, I need explain some basic concepts I mention above.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demo Page</title>
      <link>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/markdown_syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ZongyuYe.github.io/blog/markdown_syntax/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article offers a sample of basic Markdown syntax that can be used in Hugo content files, also it shows whether basic HTML elements are decorated with CSS in a Hugo theme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
